Guide to the Frank Baker Collection of Wesleyana and British Methodism, 1536-1996 and undated RL.00413
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1632-1637, 1710, 1738-1966, 1988, and undated, 17 boxes, approx. 3000 items
  - Selina Hastings, Countess of Huntingdon Letters, 1769-1774, 1789, 12 items
    Letters of Selina Hastings, Countess of Huntingdon (1707-1791). Lady Huntingdon was linked to the Wesleys and the Methodist movement for most of the first half-century of its existence. She lived a life of great contradictions and changes of heart: an ardent early supporter of JW, she finally broke with him and established her own Connexion, which still exists today in England and Sierra Leone; she sent great amounts of money to fund the purchase of slaves for a project in Georgia, but only three years later became the patroness of Phillis Wheatley, arranging the publication of her first book of poetry, which Wheatley dedicated to Huntingdon.
    - Huntingdon, S[elina]., Bath, to Mr. [Joseph] Benson, Schoolmaster at Kingswood, 1769 Oct. 11 (Box CO 4, Folder 1 of 2)
    - Huntingdon, S[elina]., Bright[on], to [Joseph] [Benson], n.p., 1770 Mar. 19 (Box CO 4)
    - Huntingdon, S[elina]., Brighton, to Mr. Benson and Williams, Masters of the College, 1770 Apr. 3 (Box CO 4)
    - Huntingdon, S[elina]., n.p., to Joseph Benson, n.p., 1770 Apr. 12 (Box CO 4)
    - Huntingdon, S[elina]., n.p., to [Joseph] [Benson], n.p., 1770 (Box CO 4)
    - Huntingdon, S[elina]., Brighton, to Mr. Benson, n.p., 1770 Apr. 22 (Box CO 4)
    - Huntingdon, S[elina]., [College] Wales, to My Dr. Sir, n.p., 1770 Nov. (?) 26 (Box CO 4)
    - [Huntingdon], [Selina], n.p., to Joseph Benson, Oxford, 1770 (Box CO 4)
    - Huntingdon, S[elina]., n.p., to Joseph Benson, n.p., 1771 Jan. 17 (Box CO 4)
    - Huntingdon, Lady, College, to Rev. Mr. English, n.p., 1774 May 31 (Box CO 4, Folder 2 of 2)
    - [Huntingdon], [Lady], Spa Fields, to Rev. Mr. Bull, London, 1789 Nov. (Box CO 4)
    - Anonymous scrap, 1771 Jan. 1 (Box CO 4)
  - Robert Hutchison Papers, 1811-1841, 1866-1868, and undated, 10 items
    Letters, photographs, and other items to, by, or about Robert Hutchison. Collection includes an invitation to dinner for the Universal Medical Institution, of which Hutchison is listed as a Steward; on the back of this is a four-week calendar with four columns of daily preaching engagements. Formal invitation card from Mr. Allan to dinner with Mr. Butterworth includes the original envelope with heavy black wax seal. Mrs. Greene included an engraved tradesman's card for "Stannard & England..." with her address handwritten on back. There is a formal letter from Mrs. Hutchison donating Wesleyan relics to the President of the conference, in which letter she emphasizes her Moravian roots.
    Note: Surname is variously spelled "Hutchison" and "Hutchinson."
    - Invitation to Universal Medical Institution Dinner, 1811 June 19 (Box CO 4)
    - Allan, [Thos.], to Mr. [Robert] Hutchison, 1820 Mar. 16 (Box CO 4)
    - Burnett, Samuel, to Robert Hutchison, London, 1838 Dec. 21 (Box CO 4)
    - Hutchison, Robert, to Samuel Burnett, 1839 Jan. 18 (draft) (Box CO 4)
    - Mrs. Greene, Bayswater, to Robert Hutchison, Stepney, 1841 Aug. 17 (Box CO 4)
    - Hutchison, Mrs. Martha, Norfolk, to the "President of the Wesleyan Conference," 1866 Nov. 26 (Box CO 4)
    - [Journal entry?] recounting visit to "grave of the family of the Rev. Charles Wesley," including list of tombstone data, 1840 Mar. 25 (Box CO 4)
    - Print of Wesley at mother's tomb, 1868 Aug. (Box CO 4)
    - Photograph of "Wesley's Tree, Winchelsea, Sussex." (Box CO 4)
    - Envelope: "R. Hutchinson Esq, Commercial Rd." (Box CO 4)
  - Thomas Jackson and Jackson Family Letters, 1824-1879, 1955, and undated, 30 items
    Letters of Thomas Jackson (1783-1873), President of the Wesleyan Methodist Conference (1838), and prolific author of books on the Wesleys and other figures in Methodist history; on his brother Samuel; and on their descendants.
    - Letters of Thomas Jackson, 1827, 1831, 1849-1872, and undated, 18 items (Box CO 4, Folder 1 of 2)
      Holograph letters, including one from to James Everett, Manchester, 1827 June 11, in which Jackson regrets that he cannot currently publish Everett's history of Manchester Methodism due to the fact that the July and August magazines have already been put to press. Jackson sometimes alludes to his writing: in a letter of Jan. 1, 1855, he mentions finishing the rough draft of his life of "the late Dr. [Robert] Newton." In a lengthy letter of Sept. 28 1869 to Mrs. [Smallpage?], he recalls what he knew of her father, Mr. Keeling, whom he first met in 1815. In a letter to Dr. Osborn, Oct. 11 1871, he praises Osborn's upcoming series of articles that effectively refute the writing of Tyernan and his interpretations of Wesley's life and other facts of Methodist history.
    - Letters of Samuel and William Jackson, Baker's transcriptions of Thomas Jackson letters, and Baker's correspondence, 1824, 1839, 1853-1879, 1955, and undated, 13 items (Box CO 4, Folder 2 of 2)
      Holograph letters of Samuel, William, and Elijah Jackson are routing correspondence about preaching appointments, etc. Correspondence of Baker with a woman trying to determine if she is the descendant of Thomas Jackson. Transcribed letters of Thomas Jackson include a long 1824 letter to Jabez Bunting in which he discusses upcoming issues of the Wesleyan Methodist Magazine and the recent arrival from Hayti of Mr. H. Dennis, a recent convert. Also included here is a sheet of Baker's notes on Dr. Humphrey Sandwith, whose papers appear later in the Correspondence Series.
  - Mrs. Leighton Letter Book, 1760-1769, 1791, and undated, 8 folders, 58 items
    Disbound letter book of a Mrs. Leighton of The Vineyards, Bath. Little information has been found about Mrs. Leighton herself, but some of FB's notes refer to her as "Mrs. Knyvett Leighton, friend and disciple of Lady Huntingdon" (see Frank Baker Papers, Subject Files, John Fletcher). Her husband was at one time an agent of the Countess. The collection consists entirely of letters to Leighton from various well-known figures in 18th-century Methodism, especially Huntingdon, whose letters comprise about half the collection. Other correspondents include John Fletcher and George Whitefield, represented elsewhere in the Baker Wesleyana collection; Henry Venn, an Anglican vicar; Martin Madan, also an Anglican clergyman; and Madan's daughter, Penelope Maitland.
    Arrangement: items have been rearranged and foldered by writer; the original sequence in the bound letter book was penciled on each letter at some point in the past. Arranged in eight folders: (1) John Fletcher; (2-4) Selina Hastings, Countess of Huntingdon; (5) Penelope Maitland; (6) Henry and E. Venn; (7) George Whitefield; and (8) unidentified writers.
    - Fletcher, John, to Mrs. Leighton, 1768 Apr. 30 and Nov. 19, 2 items (Box CO 5, Folder 1 of 8)
      Regarding Leighton's poor health; Apologies for not visiting
    - Huntingdon, Selina, to Mrs. Leighton, 1760 Sept. 5-1763 Nov. 10, 10 items (Box CO 5, Folder 2 of 8)
      Letters from Huntingdon, writing mainly from London, to Leighton, mainly in Bath.
    - Huntingdon, Selina, to Mrs. Leighton, 1765 Nov. 30-1768 Dec. 19, 10 items (Box CO 5, Folder 3 of 8)
      Letters from Huntingdon, writing from London, Brighton, or Bath, to Leighton, in Bath or London.
    - Huntingdon, Selina, to Mrs. Leighton, 1769 Mar.16-Aug. 5 and undated, 7 items (Box CO 5, Folder 4 of 8)
      Letters from Huntingdon, writing from Bath or London, to Leighton, in Bath or London.
    - Maitland, Penelope, to Mrs. Leighton, 1762 Oct. 29-1769 Jan. 6, 5 items (Box CO 5, Folder 5 of 8)
      Letters from Maitland, writing from London, to Leighton, at the Vineyards, Bath.
    - Venn, Henry and E., to Mrs. Leighton, 1763 July 9-1769 Nov. 2 and undated, 13 items (Box CO 5, Folder 6 of 8)
      Ten letters from Henry Venn, at that time vicar of Huddersfield, and three from his wife, to Mrs. Leighton.
    - Whitefield, George, to Mrs. Leighton, 1762 Oct. 14 (Box CO 5, Folder 7 of 8)
      Discussing his traveling speeches throughout London.
    - Unidentified to Mrs. Leighton, 1760-1762, 1768-1769, 1791, and undated, 10 items (Box CO 5, Folder 8 of 8)
      According to Baker's notes, some of these may be additional Whitefield letters.
  - Alexander Mather Letters 1763-1801, 1852, 1866, 1935, 1951, 17 items
    Six original letters to and from Alexander Mather (1733-1800, e.m. 1757), two of which include Baker transcriptions. General references to possible controversy: see 1796 letter. (Mather supported maintaining connection with the Church of England). Additional transcriptions of nine other letters (without originals). Life of Mather, written by Pawson (with whom Mather opposed Alexander Kilham), published in March 1801 Methodist Magazine; and a short 1935 biography of Mather, One of Wesley's Pioneer Preachers.
    - Mathers [M'Mathers?], A. M., Coleford, to Mrs. Wright Baker, Wednesberrey, Staffordshire, 1763 Jan. 8 (Box CO 6)
    - Mather, A[lexander], Bradforth, to W[illia]m Marriott, Hoxton Square, London, 1784 July 3 (Box CO 6)
    - Mather, A[lexander], Sheffield, to Lady D[arcy] Maxwell, Coates, near Edinbrough, 1788 Apr. 30 (Box CO 6)
    - Mather, A[lexander], Man[cheste?]r, to "My dear Brother," 1796 May 23 (Box CO 6)
    - West, F[rancis] A[thow], Sheffield, to Rev. [George?] Mather, [1852] July 26 (Box CO 6)
    - Bedford, J[ohn], Manchester, to Rev. George Mather, Birkenhead, 1866 Oct. 12 (Box CO 6)
    - Mather, Alexander, letters, 1766-1796 (Box CO 6)
      Nine FB transcriptions of Mather letters; written to "Wm. Orpe," "William Marriott," and "W.C. Hobbs"
    - A Farther Account of the late Mr. Alexander Mather, by John Pawson, Methodist Magazine, 1801 March (Box CO 6)
    - Alexander Mather, One of Wesley's Pioneer Preachers, by the Rev. Richard H. Wray, [1935] (Box CO 6)
  - James Montgomery Letters and Poems, 1808-1861, and undated, 10 items
    Letters, poems, and other documents by and about James Montgomery (1771-1854), Methodist layman and supporter of missions, editor of the radical newspaper Sheffield Iris, and writer of over 400 hymns. The collection includes receipts, hymns and poems (including three in memory of William Goodier, of the Rev. William Threlfall [Wesleyan missionary murdered in South Africa], and John Given), mundane correspondence, instructions for his funeral procession, and a broadside about the dedication of a monument to Montgomery, on which James Everett has written a letter stating his plans to attend.
    - Montgomery, James, to ?, 1808 June 1 (Box CO 6)
      receipt
    - Montgomery, James, ?, to ?, 1809 Feb. 17 (Box CO 6)
      Epitaph for Mr. Wm. Goodier of York (verse)
    - Montgomery, James, to Mr. J. Jones, 1819 (Box CO 6)
    - Montgomery, James, to, 1821 Mar. 3 (Box CO 6)
    - , Centenary of Wesleyan Methodism.,, 1839 Oct. 25 (Box CO 6)
      Broadside, verse by Montgomery
    - Montgomery, James, to Barnabas Shaw, Epworth, 1839 Nov. 6 (Box CO 6)
      with verses 'In Memory of the Rev. William Threlfall'
    - M[ontgomery], J[ames], "For Sunday School Union (Wesleyan)," poem, 1851 Apr. 17 (Box CO 6)
      First line: "Father of Jesus Christ our Lord"
    - , Order of the Procession on the Occasion of the Funeral of the Late James Montgomery, Esq., 1854 May 11 (Box CO 6)
      Broadside; attached to Everett letter of 1861 July 29
    - Everett, James, Sunderland, to Alfred Allott and G. B. Cocking, 1861 July 29 (Box CO 6)
      Re dedication of a statue of Montgomery
    - , The Montgomery Monument: the Statue Erected to eh Memory of the late James Montgomery, Esq., 1861 July 29 (Box CO 6)
      Broadside; attached to Everett letter of 1861 July 29; two hymns on verso, one by Montgomery
  - Henry Moore Papers, 1793, 1794, 1824, and undated, 4 items
    Letters to and from Henry Moore (1751-1844), Wesleyan Minister. He became an itinerant in 1779 and later served as John Wesley's traveling companion and amanuensis (1784-86). Moore was one of three preachers ordained by Wesley for work in England, and he was present at Wesley's death. He served as president of the conference in 1804 and 1823. The letters here are brief notes, but the broadsheet is a copy of the 1794 resolution from the Bristol trustees barring Moore from preaching at the New Room and Guinea Street Chapel in response to his celebration of Holy Communion there. This copy is addressed by Moore to Benson (in Manchester).
    This file also contains double-sided pages 2 through 10 (4 sheets, total) of what appears to be a sermon or other religious text composed in Moore's handwriting and dated "Bath, Nov. 19th 1793." Page 1, which presumably would include an intended recipient, is missing as of July 2018.
    RELATED MATERIAL: another broadsheet from August 1794, also with a long letter from Moore to Benson, appears in the Joseph Benson Papers, and Moore is the author or subject of numerous broadsheets and circular letters in the Printed Materials Series. Several letters from and to Moore appear in letter books Simpson A, WP I and II, Perronet, and Steele. Other related materials in the Rubenstein Library include the Henry Moore Papers, 1830, and his lives of John Wesley and Mary Fletcher.
    - Moore, H., to Unknown, Bath, 1793 Nov. 19 (Box CO 6)
      Letter or religious text to unknown recipient; only includes pages 2 through 10. (4 sheets total.) Page 1 determined to be missing in July 2018.
    - Trustees of the New Room and Guinea Street Chapel, to Henry Moore, Bristol, 1794 Aug. 11 (Box C0 6)
    - Moore, H[enry] to [?], 1824 Jan. 13 (Box C0 6)
    - Moore, H. and M.A., n.p., to Miss Tooth, n.p., undated (Box C0 6)
  - Elizabeth (Ritchie) Mortimer Letters, 1779-1816, 41 items
    Letters of Elizabeth Ritchie, later Elizabeth Mortimer, (1754-1835); mostly contemporary copies or drafts, rather than originals, many of them heavily edited. The core of the collection are the young Ritchie's letters to JW, in which she expresses great emotional attachment to the preacher. Her correspondence with JW from the 1770s vividly details her many bodily afflictions and the treatments she has undergone to cure them. She likewise details the illnesses of and treatments incurred by her friends. Beginning in 1779, as she begins to see many of her friends pass away, Ritchie becomes increasingly preoccupied with death and the afterlife. Autograph letters from the 1790s-1810s depict her burgeoning friendship with Sarah (Sally) Wesley, with whom she discusses matters both spiritual and mundane. And finally, a printed item from 1835--the year after Mortimer's death--transcribes an additional fifty letters, 1776-1809, written to a wide array of correspondents.
    RELATED MATERIAL: Other letters by Elizabeth (Ritchie) Mortimer, including some photocopies and transcriptions of the originals housed here, can be found in both the Frank Baker Papers, Subject Files, Elizabeth Ritchie, and in the Wesley Works Archive, Letters Series, Letters by Correspondent.
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, 1774 May 17 (Box CO 6, Folder 1 of 5)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, [Otley], to John Wesley, 1774 Jun. (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, 1774 Jul. 22 (Box CO 6)
    - [Ritchie, Elizabeth], Otley, to John Wesley, 1774 Aug. 19 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, London, 1774 Oct. 17 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, 1774 Nov. 16 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, 1775 Jan. 10 (Box CO 6)
    - [Ritchie, Elizabeth, ] Cross Hall, to John Wesley, 1775 Mar. 14 [unsigned?] (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, Liverpool, 1775 Jun. 14 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, to John Wesley, London, 1775 Nov. 15 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, Manchester, 1776 Apr. 2 (Box CO 6, Folder 2 of 5)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, to John Wesley, Edinborough, 1776 May 17 (Box CO 6)
    - [Ritchie Elizabeth], to John Wesley, 1776 Aug. 9 [?] (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, to John Wesley, London, 1776 Sept. 6 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, to John Wesley, London, 1776 Oct. 29 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, London, 1777 Feb. 6 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, to John Wesley, 1777 Feb. 18 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, to John Wesley, 1777 March 14 [correctly dated at end] (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, Bristol, 1777 Aug. 1 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Cross Hall, to John Wesley, Briston, 1777 Sept. 1 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, London, 1777 Oct. 10 (Box CO 6, Folder 3 of 5)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, 1778 Sept. 25 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Parkgate, to John Wesley, 1778 Dec. 5 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Cross Hall, to John Wesley, London, 1779 Jan. 30 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, 1779 Jun. 30 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to [Mrs. Wathen], 1779 Nov. 21 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, 1779 Dec. 21 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, 1780 Jan. 4 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to [Mrs. Wathen], 1780 Mar. 6 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Bristol, Hotwells, to John Wesley, 1780 May 20 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Publow, to John Wesley, 1780 Jul. 4 (Box CO 6, Folder 4 of 5)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, New House [near Stroud?], to John Wesley, 1780 Nov. 11 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Cross Hall, to Mrs. Horner, Liverpool, 1780 Dec. 19 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, 1781 Jan. 16 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to John Wesley, 1782 Jan. 10 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to Hester Ann Rogers, 1783 Sept. 30 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Otley, to Mrs. [Joseph] Benson, Hull, 1787 Mar. 31 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Bristol, to Miss [Sarah] Wesley, Mary'bone, London, 1793 Jan. 16 (Box CO 6)
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, Gloucester, to Miss [Sarah] Wesley, Mary'bone, 1793 Jul. 19 (Box CO 6)
    - Mortimer, Elizabeth, to Miss [Sarah] Wesley, Mary'bone, 1811 Apr. 17 (Box CO 6)
    - Printed material: Appendix, Memoirs of Elizabeth Mortimer, by Agnes Bulmer, 1836[?] (Box CO 6, Folder 5 of 5)
      Undated fragment, pp. 301-372 of what is probably a 2nd edition of this memoir, first published a year after Mortimer's death. Bulmer explains on the first page that a "series of valuable letters, from the pen of its interesting subject," came to her after the first publication of the memoir. The fragment here, which appears to be the complete appendix, transcribes approximately fifty letters from Ritchie/Mortimer, spanning 1776-1809.
    - Ritchie, Elizabeth, to Mrs. Bradburn, n.d. (Box VOLS __ (Steele))
      Verbatim copy of part of a letter
  - John Newton Letters, 1767-1781 and undated, 3 items
    Three letters by Rev. John Newton (1725-1807), a slave trader who became an Anglican priest and hymn writer, eventually came to regret his involvement in slavery, and late in life supported abolitionist William Wilberforce. He was influenced by John Wesley and George Whitefield, and his evangelical preaching navigated a middle way between Arminianism and Calvinism. He also collaborated with poet William Cowper on a volume of hymns; his own best-known hymn today is Amazing Grace. This small collection of letters is generally routine correspondence.
    RELATED MATERIAL: Newton's letters also appear in the Henry Crooke Diary, in the Volumes Series, Writings and Addresses; and the Rubenstein Library holds a 1788 edition of his abolitionist pamphlet, Thoughts Upon the African Slave Trade.
    - Newton, John, n.p., to Polly [Newton], n.p., 1767 Feb. 19 (Box C0 7)
    - Newton, John, Hoxton, to Rev. John Ryland, Jr., Northampton, 1781 Sept. 22 (Box C0 7)
    - Newton, John, to 'Miss Janny' (Miss Jane Flower), 1778 May 9 (Box C0 7)
  - Robert Newton Papers, 1809-1854, 1954, and undated, 25 items
    Letters, portrait, and other documents by, to, and about Robert Newton (1780-1854), Wesleyan Methodist minister, frequently Secretary of the Conference and four-time President (1824, 1832, 1840 and 1848), and an avid preacher (sometimes preaching twelve times per week). Routine correspondence from Newton about family, appointments, and preaching engagements. Also two letters by Newton's wife Elizabeth. There is an article about Newton from The Kingdom Overseas: Magazine of the Methodist Missionary Society, 1954. Letter and typed list of items from H.R. Brewer explains that items come from Caroline Francis Gill (thus provenance for funeral card for Robert Gill), who had unidentified connection with Robert Newton.
    - Newton, Robert, letters to Jabez Bunting, James Everett, John Roadhouse, and others, 1816 Feb. 26-1852 Oct. 1, 18 items (Box CO 7)
    - Newton, Eliza[beth], letters, 1809 and undated, 2 items (Box CO 7)
    - Scrap of letter, signed "John Scott, President, R[ober]t Newton, Secretary," (Box CO 7)
    - Portraits, 1848 and 1854 (Box CO 7)
    - Printed materials, miscellaneous, 1893 and 1954, 2 items (Box CO 7)
  - George Osborn Papers, 1789-1882, 67 items
    Letters and various documents to, about, or collected by Dr. George Osborn (1808-1891), Wesleyan Methodist Minister, elected to the Legal Hundred in 1849, twice President of the Conference (1863 and 1881), Secretary to the WM Missionary Society (1851-1868), and a scholar (editor of the 13-volume Poetical Works of John and Charles Wesley). Letters from family, William Arthur, Francis A. West, and Jabez, T.P., and W.M. Bunting. Note: some family documents (including the "Annually renewed covenant with God") are by Dr. Osborn's father, also named George. Arranged in four groups: letters to Osborn, family correspondence and documents, third party correspondence (collected by Osborn), and other items (letters from the Buntings and from Osborn, unaddressed letters, and various signatures).
    - Letters to Osborn, 1831-1890 and undated, 39 items (Box CO 7, Folder 1 of 4)
    - Family correspondence and documents, 1797-1881 and undated, 10 items (Box CO 7, Folder 2 of 4)
      Includes: Birth Certificate of Jane Osborn (sister), and Annually-renewed Covenant with God, by George Osborn (father)
    - Third party correspondence, 1838-1914, 18 items (Box CO 7, Folder 3 of 4)
      Includes: two letters to Eliza Tooth (executrix to Sarah Wesley); letter from Robert Melson to the Conference, 1853 -- Melson left conference over controversy; this letter implores the conference to seek unity, criticizing their treatment of him ("Last year, you in your way, and in my absence, tried, condemned, and punished me as guilty of Three Capital offences, of all of which I was perfectly innocent"); and 8 letters to and from James Baden Powell, a musician
    - Other correspondence including unaddressed items, 1837-1878 and undated, 22 items (Box CO 7, Folder 4 of 4)
      Includes: 5 letters from Buntings (Jabez, T. Percival, and William?) to Osborn; 3 letters from Osborn; unsigned manuscript notes and quotes on education [FB pencil note: ?Geo. Osborn]; 7 items with no addressee (not written by Osborn); signatures (Osborn's and others', including the Rev. Joseph Kipling, grandfather of Rudyard Kipling)
  - Hester Ann (Roe) Rogers Letters and Journal, 1789-1787, 28 items